Philip Whitty

Address: Nuke, Campile, New Ross, Co.Wexford

Tel: 085 - 824 6400

Email: philipwhitty92@yahoo.ie
Driver's Licence: Full Drivers Licence

PERSONAL PROFILE

Currently studying software development with Code Institute which is due to finish in December 2023.

Motivated, enthusiastic, individual with experience and exposure. Excels whilst working in a challenging and demanding fast paced environments who is motivated by deadlines, targets and delivery schedules, continually adhering to health and safety regulations and procedures. Highly organised with excellent adaptability skills, who enjoys practical learning and takes pride in continually reaching the required work standards

EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE

Nuke Construction Ltd 2021-2022

Coded Pipe Welder - Self Employed

Areas of responsibility:

- Independently receiving job contracts
- Carrying out Tig Welding process in Regeneron Pharmaceutical Plant
- Pipe Fitting and Welding procedures carried out in Sincon Engineerings workshop
- Ensuring all welds were up to standard with the specifications of weld x-rays
- Operation of Machinery including MEWP's and Forklifts
- Strict adherence to Health and Safety regulations, procedures and guidelines

Mcm Engineering 2016-2021

Coded Pipe Welder

Areas of responsibility:

- Working on Google Database Centres in the Netherlands, Denmark and Finland
- Carrying out Tig Welding process on these projects
- Pipe Fitting and Welding procedures carried out in Mcms workshop Bagnelstown
- Ensuring all welds were up to standard with the specifications of weld x-rays
- Operation of Machinery including MEWP's and Forklifts
- Strict adherence to Health and Safety regulations, procedures and guidelines

Radley Engineering 2014 – 2015

General Operative

Areas of responsibility:

- Working on a variety of projects including Glanbia Project in Killkenny and Regeneron Pharmaceutical Plant in Limerick for Radley Engineering
- Responsible for working with a variety of steel and pipework
- Carrying out carbon/ stainless bracket fabrication, in line with specifications
- Accountable for carrying out a variety of duties including cutting and experience working with gas cutting tools and drilling
- Carrying out work using TIG welding processes
- MIG welding brackets in the Radley workshop on site
- Setting up of welding plants for other welders
- Operating machinery such as MEWPs
- Ensuring all work is carried out in line with all relevant work instructions, procedures and policies
- Strict adherence to Health and Safety regulations, procedures and guidelines
- Carry out all other duties as requested

Philip Whitty CV Page 1 of 2

MCM Engineering 2013 – 2014

General Operative - Intel, Co. Kildare

Areas of responsibility:

- Assisting fitters and welder set up
- Operation of machinery such as MEWP's
- Accountable for carrying out all types of measurements
- Ensuring all work is carried out in line with all relevant work instructions, procedures and policies
- Strict adherence to Health and Safety regulations, procedures and guidelines
- Carry out all other duties as requested

Mastiff Engineering 2013

General Operative

Areas of responsibility:

- Working on the Abbot Pharmaceutical Project, Sligo
- Responsible for reading of structural steel drawings
- Erecting of steelwork
- Ensuring all work is carried out in line with all relevant work instructions, procedures and policies
- Strict adherence to Health and Safety regulations, procedures and guidelines
- Carry out all other duties as requested

EDUCATIONAL EXPERIENCE & QUALIFICATIONS

2022 Code Institute

Diploma in Full Stack Software Development

Course Content:

HTML/CSS Essentials

JavaScript Essentials

Python Essentials

GitHub

UX Essentials

Design Thinking

Advanced JavaScript

APIs and Frameworks

Agile Development

Bootstrap

Testing Code

2016 Coded Pipe Welding Programme

CETB (Cork Education & Training Board) in conjunction with Impact Training

Certification:

ASME IX and EN ISO 9606-1 and EN ISO 9606-2 Standards

Carbon Steel Pipe 6" E 6011 Root, E6013 Fill and Cap

Carbon Steel Pipe 6" PZ 6500 T.I.G Root, E7018 Fill and Cap

Carbon Steel Pipe 3" PZ 6500 T.I.G. Complete Multi Run Sequence

Stainless Steel Pipe 2" T.I.G. 316, One Run Sequence

Stainless Steel Pipe 3" Complete

Other Modules: Safe Pass, Manual Handling, Abrasive Wheels, Confined Spaces

Philip Whitty CV Page 2 of 2

2015 Intermediate Welding Programme

Machine Tools (Welding)

Manual Metal Arc Welding Intermediate

Mig Welding Intermediate Oxy-Acetylene Cutting

Safepass

T.I.G. Welding Aluminium Intermediate
T.I.G. Welding Stainless Steel Intermediate

Theory of Welding

2012 FETAC Level 5 – Sport and Recreation

2011 Leaving Certificate

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Sports – Motorsport and Soccer I take part in the Irish Hillclimb/Sprint Championship through Motorsport Wexford Played soccer for Campile United, I have won 5 league cup medals I help out with training some of Campiles underage teams

I also love attending the gym looking after my physical health and wellbeing

REFERENCES

References available on request

Philip Whitty CV Page 3 of 2